菲尔 亲爱的怎么还不睡
Oh Phil, honey you're still up.
你听听这样如何
Ok. How's this sound?
米奇尔 我很爱很爱你
Mitchell, I love you very much,
我不光爱你 更钦佩你
not only love you but I admire you
有朝一日我愿...
and someday I hope to...
你是在炒鱿鱼还是表白啊
Are you firing him or proposing to him?
亲爱的 那本来就只是份兼职
Honey, this was supposed to be a part-time job.
何况他原本也只打算干到夏天
He was gonna be done in the summer anyway.
-直接说就好了 -之前应该给他提个醒的
- Just be direct. - I should have warned him.
可叫我怎么开口
How do you tell someone
指出他懒名远扬呢
they have a reputation for being lazy?
米奇尔 懒?
Mitchell? Lazy?
没错 好几份合同他都迟迟才交
Yeah. Yeah. He handed in a couple of contracts late,
我又不好对此说三道四
but I didn't want to say anything
因为他基本算是在义务劳动了
because he's practically doing this for free.
我办不来
I can't do this!
我就不是做冷血杀手的料
This isn't the face of a cold-blooded hatchet man.
要不你来
Will you do it?
抱歉 我们把你吵醒了吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Did we wake you up?
不 一直就没睡
No, I was up.
为明天的事犯愁呢
I'm worried about tomorrow.
我的美术老师一直对我熟视无睹
My art teacher acts like I don't exist,
不过我还有最后一次机会
but I have one last chance
在期末美术展上一鸣惊人
to impress him at our year-end art fair.
我选了这幅 我们一家老小齐上阵
I've chosen this one, and I'm using my own family.
有才吧
Brilliant, right?
当我告诉他时他说 "不错啊爱丽丝"
When I told him, he said, "That's nice, Alice."
都上了一年课了
It's been a year.
爱丽丝 名字都叫错
Alice? Really?
宝贝 你这么紧张
Honey, do you think you're nervous
是因为你其实有点暗恋贾维斯老师吗
because you've got a little crush on Mr. Jarvis?
-才不是 -确定吗
- No. - Are you sure?
你瞅他那眼神我可见识过
Because I've seen the way you look at him--
我看有点暗恋他的人是你吧
Sounds like you're the one with the crush! Mm.
我只是从没碰见过不喜欢我的老师
I've just never had a teacher not like me before.
戴维斯老师对你不咋地
Well, Ms. Davis. Mm.
拜托 她是教体育的好不好
Please. She's a gym teacher.
她的执教能力就和瑟斯博士的医疗知识一样
She is to teaching what Dr. Seuss is to medicine.
怪不得她看你不顺眼
And to think she didn't like you.
那位 你怎么也没睡
You? What's your problem?
没事 就是对明天有点小兴奋
Nothing. I'm just excited for tomorrow.
学校要为我颁发奖牌
I'm getting a medal at school
因为我扑灭了一场火
because I put out a fire.
也许我长大后可以往这方面发展发展
Maybe that's what I should be when I grow up...
获奖专业户
A professional medal-getter.
卢克 出什么事了
Luke, what happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
我刚才路过时闻到了烟味而已
I was just walking by and I smelled flames.
案发当时我也在现场
I was there.
你别瞎搞
I don't like this.
我们压根就不该来这儿
We're not supposed to be in here.
你专心点帮我望风
Just keep a lookout!
再过十秒 "卢克元素"就要问世了
We're ten seconds away from creating Luketonium.
-糟了 -看看你做的好事
- Oh, crap! - Look what you did!
卢克 出什么事了
Luke, what happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
我刚才路过时闻到了烟味而已
I was just walking by and I smelled flames.
好了 各位 再不上床睡觉
Okay, guys, you're gonna be dragging tomorrow
明天都该爬不起床了 去睡吧
if you don't go to bed right now. Let's go. Go.
好 走吧 爱丽丝
Fine. Come on, Alice.
我一会儿就上楼睡
I'll be up in a minute.
"米奇尔
"Mitchell,
有一件事我实在开不了口
I can't tell you how hard...
开不了口"
How hard this..."
不 这样显得太生疏
No, that's-- no, it's not personal enough.
够了 够了
Okay, okay.
"我对你真是失望透顶 愤怒至极
"I can't tell you how hurt and angry this makes me,
一而再再而三的不遵守时间
but you've been late too many times.
请把钥匙还给我吧"
I'll need your keys."
爸爸 别这样 我错了
Daddy, no! I'm so sorry!
宝贝 我怎么没听见你下楼的声音
Honey, I didn't hear you come downstairs.
你今晚也睡不着是吧
You couldn't sleep, either?
是的
Uh, yeah.
我满脑子都在想毕业典礼的事
No, there's just, like, a lot on my mind with graduation,
该穿什么去呢 这套怎么样
and what to wear. How does this look?
等一下 你手上拎着鞋呢
Wait a second. You're carrying your shoes.
你得穿个全套我才好评价啊
How am I supposed to judge the whole outfit?
把鞋穿上
Put 'em on.
请你务必认真仔细地
So make sure you give this menu here
读一读这份菜单
a good, thorough reading.
-要份汤 -你根本看都没看
- Soup. - You didn't even look at it.
-还是汤 -仔细看看汤一栏下面的
- Soup. - Check out what's below the soup--
三明治
Sandwiches.
你有仔细看看我这裙内的风光吗
Have you check out what is below this outfit?
可不是靠吃三明治吃出来的
This doesn't come from sandwiches.
瞧啊
Look!
"杰·普里契特"
"The Jay Pritchett"?
我给弄糊涂了
I don't understand.
你这名字取自一种三明治吗
They named you after a sandwich?
不对 这三明治是以我命名的
No! They named a sandwich after me!
火鸡肉 腌肉 瑞士奶酪
"Turkey, bacon, swiss cheese,
红辣椒 凤尾鱼 全麦面包
red peppers, anchovies on wheat"?
一般人加到咸腌肉就差不多了
Most people would stop after the salty bacon,
可我这宝贝里凤尾鱼都是双层
But I double down with the anchovies.
你是做三明治呢 还是配猎鹿的诱饵呢
Were you making a sandwich or attracting deer?
老无赖骚扰你了吗 小姐
Is this bum bothering you, miss?
我真该把这一幕照下来留念
Oh, I should get a picture of this--
这破地方居然还有个女招待
An actual waitress sighting in this dump.
我本指望靠你那三明治来招揽生意
I took a chance and put in an order for your sandwich,
结果多数人更愿意"杰·普里契特"打包[走人]
although most people like their Jay Pritchetts to go.
这是唱的哪一出啊
What's happening?
歌洛莉亚 来见过玛克辛
Gloria, it's Maxine.
你就是下嫁杰的那位
So you're married to Jay.
你把你的导盲犬拴在哪里了
Where'd you tie up your seeing eye dog?
不 不是 我没有瞎
No, no, I'm not, um...
好吧 我听懂了 听懂了
Okay, I get it. I get it.
那颈部医生的电话 我一直推荐你去看的那个
Here's that number for that neck doctor I want you to see.
-谢了 -你脖子怎么了
- Thanks. - What's wrong with your neck?
三十年了 他总说这是玩手球时受的伤
For 30 years, I've been hearing it's a handball injury.
不过每次压力一大 病就加重
But it always seems to get worse with stress.
我估计是给最近那审计闹的
Maybe it's that audit he's got coming up.
-审计 -没多大事
- Audit? - It's nothing.
真贴心 他不想让你操心
Oh, isn't that cute? He doesn't want you to worry.
你的三明治来了
Here's your sandwich.
现在轮到你操心了
Now you should worry.
瞧瞧 我视如己出的宝贝
Look at it-- my prettiest child.
你怎么不告诉我脖子的事呢
Why didn't you tell me about your neck?
没啥大事 尝一口
It's fine. Take a bite.
-你们公司要被审计吗 -没事
- Your company's getting audited? - Nothing!
熬三天就过去了
Three bad days, then it's over.
开吃吧 我急着等你的评价呢
Come on! I'm--I'm anxious to hear what you think.
尝出点滋味了吧
I see it growing on ya.
跟玛克辛第一次尝它时一样
It's like Maxine when she first tried it.
-你知道她也 -我不喜欢这玩意儿
- You know, she-- - I don't like it.
你还没全吃完呢
You probably didn't get all--
杰 我吃过了 不喜欢
Jay, I try it. I don't like it.
这就是你的评价吗
That's all you can say?
这玩意儿味道差极了
It tastes bad in my mouth.
就像一条鱼和一只火鸡
It's like a fish and a turkey
用胡椒做武器斗个你死我活
beat themselves to death with a pepper.
你尽管说 虽说有点吹毛求疵
Okay, fair enough. Maybe a little picky, though,
可每次你做完哥伦比亚特色菜
from someone who prepared a colombian specialty
不也会反问我 "你怎么不尝一口蹄子
and said, "Why are you not eating the hooves?
那可都是精华啊"
They're the best part."
我回来了
I'm back!
小卡舅夫你回来了
Oh, hey, uncle Cam.
谢谢你那天晚上来接我
Oh, thanks again for picking me up last night.
小意思 不过你得更加小心才是
You're welcome, but you have to be more careful.
我才是负责任的那个
I was the responsible one.
丽萨喝多了 我收了她的车钥匙
Lisa was drinking, and I took her keys,
-然后 -我明白
- and then e-- - I understand.
舅夫高三那会儿也有过疯狂之夜
My senior year, I had a pretty crazy night myself
俺们农场那些碎玉米啊翻犁头什么的
involving a bottle of corn mash and an overturned plow.
-不是吧 -你是没见过当时那阵仗
- Seriously? - Yeah. You don't know terror until you've had to
我直视着密苏里州骑警的双眼
stare down the eyes of a Missouri State trooper
为自己酒后扰乱治安辩解
and talk your way out of a P.U.I.
亲爱的你又不喝咖啡的
Honey, you don't drink coffee.
我昨晚大半夜都没睡踏实
I do when I've been up half the night
担心我那只完工了三分之一的作业
worrying about a project that's only one-third done,
还有一条围裙要缝 一副风景画要画
and I still have an apron to sew, scenery to paint,
再加上工作表全乱套了 所以...
plus my normal crushing workload. So...
除非你有个更好的办法帮我提神
Unless you have a better way for me to stimula--
哦天呐
Oh, god.
老天 咖啡真苦
God, coffee's bitter.
你这是第一次喝吗
That was your first sip?
好了 我拿来了砂锅
Okay, I got the chafing dish,
盐罐和胡椒罐 黄金搭档
salt and pepper shakers-- perfect matches, both.
我得把葡萄重新摆放一下
I may have to readjust my grapes.
是吗 那我还是回避一下吧
Oh. Ow. I'll just give you a little privacy.
"灯光秀"又回来了
Welcome back to the light show. Hi.
嗨 莉莉
Hi, lily.
嗨 爹地
Hi, daddy.
莉莉
Lily...
亲爱的 不行
Sweetheart, no.
不行 不行 今天不能这么玩
No, no, no, no. We're-- we're not gonna do that today.
等一下 克莱尔 实际上
Actually-- actually, Claire,
我们正在尽量不对女儿说"不"字
We're--we're trying not to use the word "No" So much.
我们刚读过的一本书上说
We just read a book that said
孩子们会从"不"字学会叛逆
children learn to rebel against that word.
所以我们要换种活动去诱导她
So we redirect her into a new activity instead.
看好了
Oh. Here--well, just watch this.
乖女儿 爹地在这儿
Lily, sweetie, hi. It's daddy here.
你想听点音乐吗
Would you like to listen to some music?
好的 听吧
Okay. There you go.
瞧
See?
每一代人都觉得
Every new generation thinks
自己掌握了教育孩子的秘诀
they have cracked the code on child rearing.
最新的秘诀 就是不要说"不"
What's the latest theory? Never say "No."
"不"就是老娘每天在家里的口头禅
I say "No" Every day in this house.
可夜半回床上 她就忍不住狂喊"真爽"[是]
But at night, she's a "Yes" Machine.
没有
No.
看来你的新办法非但不能让她消停会儿
Oh, it doesn't seem that she is redirecting her own energy
还让我们浪费了更多电
as much as using a lot of ours.
但你注意到没 她正在逐渐把注意力
But do you see how she's slowly transitioning
从灯光转移到音乐上吗
from the lights to the music?
对 对 我看到了
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
轻松得都让我 忘记曾经必须亲自
It's hard to believe there was ever a time
费口舌说"住手停下"的时光了
when we just said, "Stop doing that."
天呐 别玩垃圾处理器
Oh. The garbage disposal.
莉莉 不行 不行
Lily, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不如我们诱导你去睡个小觉吧
Now let's redirect you into a nap, huh?
实际上我们在尝试新办法
Actually, we're doing this new thing
孩子想睡觉的时候 让她自己告诉我们
where we let her tell us when she wants to take a nap.
这叫"我的睡眠我做主"
It's called "Being your own nap captain."
过来 乖女儿
Come on, sweetie.
菲尔
Phil.
你按门铃了吗
Did you ring the doorbell?
没有 拿着咖啡没腾出手
Oh, no, 'cause I have these two coffees.
一杯给你
One is for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的生活大致如下 一份全职工作
Here's my life-- a full-time job,
一个三岁的女儿 还有一个正待领养
a 3-year-old, and a second one on the way.
加上为了帮忙
and as a favor,
我答应帮菲尔他们公司做一点事
I agreed to do a little work for Phil's agency.
麻烦就是 我太出色了
The problem is, I'm very good,
我做得越好 他们越离不开我
and the more I do, the more they want me.
一些任务我甚至故意晚些交工
I-I even turned in a few assignments late
为了让他们不要对我死缠烂打
so that they'd fall out of love with me a little bit.
可不就得这样
Right.
你在门外站了多久了
How--how long have you been standing here?
你没事吧
Are--are you-- are you all right?
没事
Oh, yeah.
你眼睛怎么眨个不停
'cause you're-- you're really blinking.
我一有压力就眨眼
I'm a stress blinker,
尤其是跟别人对峙的时候
and what really gets me going is confrontation.
很讨厌那感觉 能避免就避免
I hate it. I-I avoid it at all costs.
手足无措
Terrible at it.
有一次 我想跟一个女孩提分手
Once, I, uh, I tried to break up with a girl,
我绕了好大一个圈子
and I danced around it so much,
结果她都不知道我跟她分手了
she didn't know I had broken up with her.
结果我跟她一结婚就是20年
20 years later, we're still married.
我 非常 抱歉
I am... Really... Sorry...
咖啡都凉了
about the cold coffee.
没那么凉 还温[卢克热]着呢
It's not that cold. It's lukewarm, so...
-我得走了 -你用那词让我想到个事儿
- Okay, so-- - Funny story about that expression--
我家娃还小的时候 我们...
when the kids were younger, um, we had a, uh,
有一个嬉水池
a wading pool...
间或卢克总捣鼓出点乱子
and occasionally, Luke would have an accident,
然后艾丽克斯就吓得直叫
and, um, Alex would scream,
然后我们就说 亲爱的没事
and we'd say, um, "It's okay, honey,
只不过把水"卢克热"一下
he's just making it lukewarm."
-那么 -我得走了
- Wow, so-- - So I gotta get going,
-回头见 -好吧 等一下
- but I-I'll see-- - Okay, wait!
我还是开门见山地说吧
I'm just gonna come straight out and say it.
米奇尔 你在我们公司做得很好
Mitchell, you've done a wonderful job for the agency
既然你决定帮我们这个小忙
Since you decided you'd help us out for just a little bit.
而我们也不该再麻烦你 对吧
And we couldn't ask for more, could we?
但我不希望合作就此结束
I wish it didn't have to end.
如果能由我决定 你可以一直干下去
In fact, if it was up to me, you'd stay on forever...
-菲尔 菲尔 -但我说了不算数 对吧
- Phil, Phil... - But it is not just up to me, is it?
-所以 -菲尔我早知会如此
- So... - I... Phil, I saw this coming,
而且 你看啊
And--and look...
我逃了 我找了个借口就跑了
I bailed. I made an excuse and left.
但我必须和他实话实说
But I-I-I've gotta be straight with him.
"菲尔 我不能永远帮你们公司干活"
"Phil, I cannot stay on with your firm forever."
天呐 那一定会让他很伤心
Oh! God, it's gonna crush him.
要不让克莱尔帮我传个话
Maybe I can get Claire to do it.
挺简单就说出口了嘛
Well, that was easy!
我们以你为豪
We're really proud of you, buddy.
颁奖典礼上见
See you at the ceremony.
-你不是英雄 -是我把火灭了
- You're not a hero. -I put out a fire.
你自己点的火
A fire you started.
-当时是不是起火了 -是的
- Was there a fire? - Yes.
-火是我灭的吗 -这不
- Did I put it out? - That's not--
你就回答这个问题
Answer the question.
是的
Yes.
他们要为此给我发奖
I'm getting an award for it.
如果他们要给纵火的发奖
If they gave awards for starting fires,
我还会再拿一项奖
I'd be getting one of those, too.
卢克 我知道你是个有良心的人
I know you have a conscience, Luke.
你看这国旗 它是正义的象征
Do you see this flag? It stands for justice.
等火警部的人来了后
So when that fire marshall gets here,
我知道你会注视着国旗
I know you're going to look at that flag
做正确的事情
and do the right thing.
你回家路上一句话也没说
You were very quiet all the way home.
你不高兴 是不是因为我冲老太太摁喇叭了
Are you upset at me because I honked at that old lady?
一般来说 摁喇叭是司机的事
Normally, we leave the honking to the driver,
但我已经习惯了
but I'm used to it.
是因为那三明治吗
Is it because of the sandwich?
你其实可以吃掉一大半
Ah, you maybe could have eaten half of it...
然后再美言几句
said a couple of nice things.
杰 不就是个三明治嘛
It's just a sandwich, Jay.
歌洛莉亚 这不是三明治的问题
It's not about the delicious sandwich, Gloria.
而是你尊不尊重他人感受的问题
It's about being respectful of a person's feelings.
但我只是实话实说啊
But I was just being honest.
一段感情中并不是每件小事
You don't have to be honest
你都要实话实说告诉另一半的
about every little thing in a relationship.
有时该说实话 有时不该说
Some things you say, some things you don't.
有什么事你没说实话
What are the things that you don't say?
歌洛莉亚 我实在不想谈这个
Gloria, I really don't wanna do this anymore.
真的吗
Oh, really?
可你不能光顾着教训我
But you cannot just try to teach me a lesson,
-却不... -好好
- and then not even.. - Okay, fine.
虽然不想这么说
I don't say this,
可有件事确实让我有点烦
But it... Bothers me a little bit
你说话的动静有些许 聒噪
That you're just a tiny bit... loud.
-聒噪 -也不是每时每刻
- Loud? - Not all the time.
只是 在你开口说话时
Only when you, you know, when you talk.
我让你觉得丢人吗
So I embarrass you?
-歌洛莉亚 -干嘛
- Gloria... - What?
我说话又太聒噪了吗
Am I being too loud again?
好吧 又有得斗了
All right. Buckle up.
我现在要去洗衣服了
Oh, I'm gonna go and try to do the laundry,
我会蹑手蹑脚轻言轻语地
and I'm gonna do it very quietly
不想烦你 或许曼尼能帮我
so I don't bother you. Maybe Manny can help me.
曼尼
Manny!
-意思到了就好了 -曼尼
- I get it. - Manny!
我懂了
I get it.
现在你一点声都没有了
Now you're not even making any noise.
葡萄放太多了
Okay, this is way too many grapes,
而且这勺子不够复古
and this spoon is modern day,
如果我们用了 餐桌上的所有人都会惊异于
so if we use it, everyone at the table has to react in shock
这从未来穿越来的勺子
at the spoon from the future.
好吧 这下穿越进下水道了
Okay. And that went down the drain.
你赶紧去打个盹吧
And you need a nap.
你才要打个盹呢
You need a nap.
我捡到了 又掉了 擦
I got it. Ooh, I lost it. Shoot.
需要我帮你减少一些外界干扰吗
Let me know if I can eliminate any distractions for you.
捡到了 我手指够到了 快了
Oh, I got it. No, I got a finger on it. There it is.
又掉了
Oh, lost it again.
或许你该等它自己出来
Maybe you should just wait until it comes to you.
你懂的 让勺子自己做主嘛
You know, make it the captain of its own spoon platoon.
克莱尔 我知道你想说什么 但是
I understand the point you're making, Claire, but...
啊 我被卡出了
Oh! Now I'm stuck.
是啊 小卡 你确实卡住了
Yeah, Cam, you are stuck.
你卡在了一个根本不管用的方法论上
You are stuck on a philosophy that clearly doesn't work.
有时 你必须对孩子说"不"
Sometimes, you need to say "No" to a child.
是啊 有时 你也需要对一个大人说"不"
Yeah, and sometimes you need to say "No" to an adult.
不 克莱尔 我不需要别人教我怎么带小孩
No, Claire. No, I don't need help raising my child.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
不好意思
Sorry.
看来 我还有很多要学
Guess I-I do have a lot to learn.
现在 我就想看看
Right now, I-I'm looking forward to learning
你能不能及时抽出手来
if you will get your arm out of there
别等莉莉打开了水槽垃圾粉碎器的开关
before Lily gets to the garbage disposal switch.
莉莉 宝贝儿
Um... Lily, sweetie!
克莱尔 你能帮帮忙吗
C-can you do something, please, Claire?
我愿意 真的 我愿意
I would like to. Really, I would,
可我只会说"不"
But I would probably just say "No"
那会打击她的自信心和自尊心
and shred her confidence and mangle her self-esteem.
好啦 我错了 看这儿
Okay, fine! I'm sorry! Just--here,
-阻止她 阻止她 宝贝 -看你怎么办
- Stop her! Stop her! Sweetie! - What to do with you?
克莱尔 好吧
Claire! Okay!
真好玩
Ohh! Yes!
-你觉得这很好玩是吧 -当然了
- You think that's funny, don't ya? - Oh, sure.
太坏了 克莱尔 你太坏了
Yes. Well, it's wicked, Claire. It's wicked.
过来 我们该走了 莉莉
Come on. We're leaving, lily!
莉莉
Lily!
简直就是行为艺术
It's living art.
整整90秒我们就笔直站在那
We stay perfectly still for 90 seconds,
几乎纹丝不动
basically doing nothing.
我第一个老婆在床上也一动不动
Sounds like my first wife.
不是吧 她在我身上动得可欢呢
I don't know. She always moved for me.
你们都承认只能坚持90秒就行了
As long as you both agree it was only 90 seconds.
一石在手 二傻出糗
Two nerds with one stone!
我就爱在办公室里工作
I love working in an office.
那是你小舅子吗 你不是把他解雇了吗
Is that your brother-in-law? I thought you fired him.
是啊 上班路上
I did, before work.
那他在这儿干嘛
Then what's he doing here?
愤愤不平吗 他看起来是有点
Is he disgruntled? He looks disgruntled.
不 他生下来就这德性
No, he always looks like that.
有事吗
Hey. How's it going?
听着
Hey, hey. Listen--
我知道这很尴尬
Okay, I know this is uncomfortable...
但我们需要谈谈我在这里的前景
but we really need to talk about my future here.
但我 我以为我们
But I-I-I thought we--
不 我知道我让你误以为
No, I know. I know I led you to believe
我能一直在这里工作下去
that I'd be able to stay on here indefinitely,
而且
And--and... O-okay,
别眨眼了
Don't get all blinky. Oh.
-也不全是坏消息 -好吧
- No, it's not all bad news, okay? - Okay.
就按我们商量好的 我会待到七月
You will have me until July, like we agreed.
-挺好 -对
- Okay, great. - Yes.
你能麻溜儿地跟我坐电梯下去一趟吗
Hey, could you jump on the elevator with me real quick?
-行 -要麻烦你帮我从车里搬点东西上来
- Yes. - Yes. I could use a hand carrying up some stuff from my car.
对了 要先拿点空箱子 对吗
Oh! My goodness. I probably need some empty boxes, don't I?
要不你先下去
You know what? You head down,
我们在玻璃门那儿会合
I'll meet you at the glass doors.
我还想说什么来着 是什么呢
There was something else. What was it?
就在脑边了 对了 你被炒了
I know it's in there. Oh, yeah, you're fired.
什么 被炒了
What? F-fired?!
这门怎么了这是
W-what's going on with these things?
你在帮忙打开吗
You trying to open 'em?
我想我最好去叫些帮手
I guess I better... get somebody.
等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait--
你干嘛要炒我
You're firing me?
我压根就不喜欢这份工作啊
I-I don't even like this job.
这样不安全
That can't be safe.
-有人被困在里面了吗 -被炒的那个人
- Is someone trapped in there? - The guy they fired.
那个懒货吗
Oh, the lazy guy?
懒货?
Lazy?!
你迟交过一些材料
You handed in a couple of things late.
我该事先给你提个醒的
I should have warned you.
我不擅长告诉别人坏消息
I'm terrible at breaking bad news.
那你为什么要跑到我家
Well, then why did you come over to my house
把我吹得跟朵花似的
and tell me how great I was?
我那是想炒你鱿鱼
That was me trying to fire you!
上次这么纠结还是20年前
I haven't felt like this since I tried to
我打算跟克莱尔闹分手
break up with Claire 20 years ago.
又有人困在里面了吗
Someone's stuck again?
他们刚炒掉的那个态度恶劣的律师
That lawyer with the attitude they just fired.
人都说是因为你态度恶劣
They said it was your attitude,
摆着谱像是给了我们多大恩惠
like you were doing us a favor.
难道不是这样吗
I was doing you a favor!
-他干了什么了这么遭人恨 -偷懒
- Why didn't he get the service like everyone else? - Lazy
别担心 他打不着你
Don't worry. He can't get you.
我在里面困了两个小时
Two hours I was stuck in there
整个办公室的人都来围观
with the entire office of people staring at me,
我 我最后只好躺下
I-I finally had to lie down.
让我的形象更加恶劣
doesn't help my reputation
瞧这熊样
Figures.
你们干的棒极了
You guys nailed it.
小兄弟 神乎其神的
Dude, that was surreal.
老爸 拜托
Dad, come on!
我们还剩一分钟准备时间
We have a minute to set up!
米奇尔和小卡在哪里
Where are Mitchell and Cam?
曼尼 谢谢你之前那些关于国旗的演说
Hey, Manny. Thanks for what you said before about the flag.
真的让我思绪良多
It really got me thinking.
我知道你是有良知的 卢克
I knew you had a conscience, Luke.
更重要的是 你有一颗好...
And more importantly, you've got a good...
你不是吧
You didn't.
没错 多亏了你
Yep. And thanks to you,
我让他们移师国旗下完成了仪式
I had them move the ceremony to right under the flag.
我会给你张签名照的
I'll sign a picture for you.
你们来了 就怕你们放我鸽子
Oh, there you are. I was afraid you weren't coming.
是商量着要不要来的
It was a discussion.
如果我们决定不来
If we weren't gonna show up,
我们肯定会提前告诉你
we would have clearly let you know,
而不是在公共场合羞辱你
and not humiliated you in public.
权当是安慰吧
If it's any consolation,
我们新雇的律师
the lawyer we hired to replace you
已经对那个电梯公司发起诉讼了
is already suing the elevator company.
你坐到我手上了
You're sitting on my hand.
好歹你双手都在
Be thankful you have two.
我今天可差点废掉一只
I almost lost one today.
别像个孩子似的
Oh, stop being such a baby.
她离那个开关十万八千里呢
She was nowhere near that switch.
安静点 我们要开始了
shh! Keep your voices down.We're about to go on.
你看着我干什么
Why you looking at me?
我很聒噪吗 大家都这么认为吗
Am I too loud? Is that what everybody thinks?
-怎么了 -她这是事出有因
- What? - There's a backstory here
我就不折磨你们耳朵了
you don't wanna know about.
-我想要火鸡 -忍着 小甜心
- I want turkey. - Save your appetite, baby girl.
别忘了 结束后
And don't forget, afterwards,
我们要去"连记餐馆"吃个简餐
we're going to Lenny's for a bite to eat--
如果在乎我 到时候就多吃点
more than a bite if you value my feelings.
太好了 我们能看到玛克辛了
Oh! Great, we get to see Maxine.
什么 你也知道玛克辛吗
What? You know Maxine, too?
-我们都知道玛克辛 -超爱的
- Oh, we all know Maxine. - Love.
她有这世上第二棒的拥抱
Second-best hugger in the world,
仅次于伯特·雷诺兹 说来话长
after Mr. Burt Reynolds. Story to follow.
好了 90秒后就大功告成了
All right, guys, this will all be over in 90 seconds.
-姿势都给我定好 -好
- Hold your poses. - Okay.
我想给"迷死人"老师留个好印象
I really wanna impress Mr. Gorgeous.
是贾维斯老师 闭嘴
Jarvis! Shut up.
米奇 我知道现在说这个不合适
Hey, Mitch, I know this isn't a good time,
我只是想要你知道
I-I just want you to know,
-我真的 -我知道 菲尔 你很抱歉
- I'm really-- - I know, Phil.You're really sorry, okay?
但我需要一点时间平复心情 好吗
But this is gonna take me a little time to get over, all right?
事实上 我是想让你把公司停车卡还我
Actually, I was gonna say I'm really gonna need your parking pass.
什么
What?!
下一个舞台演出是由艾丽克斯·邓菲带来的
Our next stage presentation will be Alex Dunphy's interpretation
对诺曼·洛克威尔1943年的作品
of Norman Rockwell's 1943 painting,
《免于匮乏的自由》的解读
"Freedom from want"
你晚上怎么能安心睡觉 卢克
How do you sleep at night, Luke?
把奖牌挂我脖子上呗
With a medal around my neck.
-我想吃火鸡 -莉莉 不要
- I want turkey. - Lily, no!
她应该不懂这个词吧
She doesn't understand that word.
收声 克莱尔
Cram it, Claire.
管好你的孩子 小卡
Control your child, Cam.
又不是啥难事 我养了三个呢
It's not that difficult. I've raised three.
-真的吗 -小卡
- Really? - Cam!
你为什么不问问海莉昨晚几点回的家
Why don't you ask Haley what time she got home last night?
小卡舅夫
Uncle Cam!
对不起亲爱的 伤及无辜了
Sorry, dear. Collateral damage.
他这是在说什么呢
What is he talking about?
你的手臂在抖
Your arms are shaking.
怎么着
Oh, yeah,
那完美无缺的玛克辛肯定比我做得好
I'm sure that the great Maxine can do a better job!
随便你怎么批判我的教育方式 小卡
You can criticize my parenting all you like, Cam,
但我儿子刚得了枚奖牌
but my son just won a medal.
那火是他自己放的
For a fire he started.
卢克 是真的吗
Luke, is that true?
还要多久 我快撑不住了
How long? It's getting heavy!
那停车卡你是别指望拿回去了
You're not getting that parking pass back.
我试过委婉地告诉你
I tried to let you down easy.
你不懂得如何与人交流 菲尔
You don't know how to talk to people, Phil.
比如克莱尔当时完全不知道你把她甩了
It's just like when Claire didn't even know you dumped her.
-什么 -爸爸什么时候甩过你
- What? - When did dad dump you?
我没甩她 只是想甩而已
I didn't dump her! I just tried to!
撑不住啦
I am losing it!
再坚持几秒种
Just a few more seconds!
我要吃火鸡
I want turkey.
莉莉 不
Lily, no!
我们真的在尝试少提这个字眼
We really are trying to not say that word.
B-
B-minus,
不过聊以慰藉的是
But there was a silver lining.
"我看好你哦 艾丽克斯"
"I expected more, Alex."
艾丽克斯[总算叫对名字了]
Alex!
我打电话给海莉告诉她
I am gonna call Haley and tell her
我们不去"连记"吃了
we're not going to that deli.
我实在受不了小卡了
I can't take another minute of Cam.
虽然我自己都不太确信
You know, I'm not even sure
能被这套全新的家教理论说服
I believe all these new parenting theories,
但让她来对我指手画脚 让我死了算了
but I'll be damned if I'm gonna let her tell me they're wrong.
晚饭我看还是免了吧
We are not going to dinner.
我试过那个三明治了
I tried that sandwich.
就那么回事 你不吃也没事
It's not that good. You're not missing anything.
我才不稀罕卢克和他的傻帽奖牌
I sure won't miss seeing Luke and that stupid medal.
可我向来循规蹈矩 怎么不给我个奖牌
I play by the rules. Where's my medal?
杰可以和那个玛克辛一起吃
Jay can stay with that Maxine.
她可没我这么聒噪
She's not loud like me.
凭心而论 你给人支招时常常不过脑
In fairness, you can be a little quick to give advice.
我向来一心帮助他人
Well, I'm always ready to help,
如果你是这意思的话 那没错
if that's what you mean, yeah.
但如果你不注意下措词 听起来就有点
Yeah, but if you're not careful, it can come off a little...
"自以为知"
Know-it-all-y.
这是哪国语言
That's not a word.
你想说的应该是
What you mean to say is,
听起来会让人觉得有点"自以为是"
it can come off like I know it all.
我一直就是这个做派
I've always been this way.
所以当时我才想甩了你
That's why I wanted to break up with you.
说"炒掉"这个词根本不合适
The word "Fired" doesn't even apply.
帮忙而已 怎么能被炒掉呢
You can't get fired from a favor.
好了 亲爱的 你还是别去想了
Okay, sweetie, maybe you should just let it go.
就像我常说的 耿耿于怀不如放手释怀
Like I always say, it's better to carry a tune than a grudge.
好吧 你从来没说过这话
Okay, you... you've never said that, but...
那你对克莱尔的耿耿于怀又怎么说
And--and what about this grudge you're holding against Claire?
也没见你放手释怀啊
I don't see you trading that in for a tune.
那完全不是一回事
That is completely different.
她诋毁了我为人父母的能力
She insulted my parenting skills.
你就承认吧 有时候你是老虎屁股摸不得
Which, you have to admit, you can be pretty defensive about.
好吧 也许我俩都过于敏感了
Okay, so maybe we both can be a little sensitive.
不 不是
N-no. No.
不 那完全不是同一回事
No. These--these are-- these are not equal.
你完全不了解被炒掉是什么感觉
No, you have no idea what it feels like to be fired.
我了解 我被炒过 谁没有啊
Yes, I do. I've been fired. Everyone has.
我没有
Not me.
-从来没有? -没有
- Never? - No.
没有 我在工作上向来很优秀
Nope, I've always been very good at what I do.
也许你只是第一次
So then maybe what you're feeling
对你的工作产生了一点危机感
is a little insecure about your work for the first time.
纯属废话[猪食]
That's hogwash.
作为真正见识过猪食的人
As someone who's seen actual hogwash,
我可以保证还没到那份上
I can assure you that it's not.
我不理解为什么玛克辛这么招你烦
I don't know why you're so bothered by Maxine.
她人不错啊
She's nice.
好啊 那不如你 杰还有玛克辛
Oh, good! Why don't you, Jay, and Maxine
一起生活吧 快乐地吃着三明治直到永远
live together, eating sandwiches forever?!
小哥斗胆给你把把脉 老妈
Can I float a theory here, mom?
你好像是吃醋了
You sound like you're jealous.
得了吧
Please!
我吃那个女人的醋
Me jealous of that woman?
我就是看不顺眼他们讲话的样子
I just don't like the way they talk to each other!
还有那私房笑话
And the little jokes,
她对他的生活了如指掌
and she knows everything about his life!
就是让我感觉
Just makes me feel like, em...
这是吃醋吗
Is that jealous?
我的妈呀
Ay, my poor sisters.
就你吗 我以为你们全家人都会来呢
Just you? I thought the whole family was swinging by.
谁知道是怎么回事
Who knows what they're doing?
现在都看彼此不顺眼
Right now, they're all sniping at each other.
谁需要他们啊
Ah, who needs 'em?
是啊 只要我还有你 玛克辛
Right. As long as I have you, Maxine...
我五点就下班
I'm off in five.
卢克
Hey, Luke!
这亮闪闪的奖牌是什么呀
What's with all the hardware?
他在学校制造了火灾 并且撒了谎
Well, he set fire to a school and lied about it.
这年头屁大点事也要发个奖牌
You know they give medals for anything these days.
明天要还回学校
It's going back tomorrow.
他没什么机会能得奖牌
He doesn't get a lot of medals.
我真的需要来一个"爱的抱抱"
I just really need one of these.
使劲抱吧
Don't hold back. Oh!
宝贝外孙女来了
My girls. There they are. Hi.
大家好啊 好啊
Hello, hello. Hi, all.
小卡
Hey, Cam. Hey!
快来
Come on in!
你能来太好了
I, uh, I appreciate your coming.
还有 我真的真的 谢谢
And, again, I really, really--Thank you.
-她来了 -看谁来了
- There she is. - Well, look who made it.
你好 玛克辛 见到你很高兴
Hola, Maxine. So nice to see you.
我去给你们拿菜单
Let me get you some menus.
不需要
We don't need it.
都要"杰·普里契特"三明治
It's Jay Pritchetts all around!
歌洛莉亚 如果你的三明治不要凤尾鱼
Gloria, if you want your sandwich without anchovies,
我不会生气的
I won't be offended.
不过这就要改名为"杰克·菲德曼"了
Of course, then it'll be a Jack Feldman.
-兄弟 -修电梯的来了吗
- Hey, man. - Is the repair guy here?
在修了
He's working on it.
听我说
Um, listen, uh,
今天是卡蒂的生日 司格普的助理
It's Katie's birthday, Skip's assistant.
30好几了 大龄剩女
Big 3-0. Still no ring.
你叫醒我就为说这个吗
You woke me up to tell me that?
不是 我给你拿了点蛋糕
No, no. I-I grabbed you some cake.
确定不是员工也可以吃吗
Oh, sure it's not for employees only?
好吧 就知道会这样
Okay. Had that coming.
你跟谁说话呢 菲尔
Who are you talking to, Phil?
-米奇尔 -谁
- Mitchell. - Who?
米奇尔 我的小舅... 那懒鬼
Mitchell, my br-- uh, the lazy guy.
我只是来帮你忙而已
I was doing you a favor.
好吧 蛋糕给我 我饿了
All right, just give me the cake. I'm hungry.
不要啊
No!